In order to better simulate clothing and adjust clothing details, you can select the range of detachment when detaching clothing.
To activate the soft-select detachment, please open the simulation and select the move tool, then select the soft-select detachment option in the background right of the 3D window.
Or you can press Shift E to activate this function.
After activating the soft-select detachment function, a spring that is used to set attributes will pop up.
The settings in this spring are divided into two parts.
In the above options, you can see the settings for the detachment range.
Here you can set the soft-select detachment type, range, and detachment degree.
In the following options, we can set the measurement method of the soft-select range, whether it shows the range brush, whether it is used only in the selected version, and whether it shows the weight.
The range brush is randomly opened.
When you move the mouse, you will see two circles that indicate the soft-select.
The outer circle indicates the range of soft selection, and the inner circle indicates the degree of detachment.
Now we turn on the full weight display.
When you turn on the full weight display, the soft-select part will show green.
The soft-select type is divided into two types, the curve and the straight line.
The function curve at the bottom indicates the strength of the soft-select with the degree of detachment changed from the center of the brush.
In different soft-select types, the soft-select curve is different. In addition, the curve is also affected by the degree of detachment.
Now let's set the soft-select range and the degree of detachment to the highest to see the difference between the two soft-select types.
When we set it to the straight line type, the soft-select center range is very small.
When we set it to the curve type, the soft-select center range is wider.
Return all values to default settings.
There are two ways to measure the range, surface measurement and straight line measurement.
When the measurement is set to surface, the soft-select will be applied to the surface of the version you click with the brush.
Therefore, your choice will only affect the selected version.
Press and hold the shift key to press to turn off the Kunden mode.
If the method of measuring the range is set to straight line, the soft-selection will be applied to all 3D space such as the back of the mouse.
Press and hold the shift key to press to turn off the button.
This measurement method is more suitable for soft selection of multi-layered clothing
By clicking on the button that only works for selected panels, your soft selection will only work for selected panels
Not affected by the range measurement method of selection
This option is very effective for panels that are glued together after some simulation
Thank you for watching, see you in the next video
Thanks for watching